<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Surfacers on Cloudprober</title>
    <link>https://cloudprober.org/surfacers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Surfacers on Cloudprober</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 17:24:32 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cloudprober.org/surfacers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stackdriver (Google Cloud Monitoring)</title>
      <link>https://cloudprober.org/surfacers/stackdriver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 17:24:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudprober.org/surfacers/stackdriver/</guid>
      <description>Cloudprober can natively export metrics to Google Cloud Monitoring (formerly, Stackdriver) using stackdriver surfacer. Adding stackdriver surfacer to cloudprober is as simple as adding the following stanza to the config:
surfacer { type: STACKDRIVER } This config will work if you&#39;re running on GCP and your VM (or GKE pod) has access to Cloud Monitoring (Stackdriver). If running on any other platform, you&#39;ll have to specify the GCP project where you want to send the metrics, and you&#39;ll have to configure your environment for Google Application Default Credentials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surfacers</title>
      <link>https://cloudprober.org/surfacers/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 17:24:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudprober.org/surfacers/overview/</guid>
      <description>One of the biggest strengths of cloudprober is that it can export data to multiple monitoring systems, even simultaneously, just based on simple configuration. Cloudprober does that using a built-in mechanism, called surfacers. Each surfacer type implements interface for a specific monitoring system, for example, pubsub surfacer publishes data to Google Pub/Sub. You can configure multiple surfacers at the same time. If you don&#39;t specify any surfacer, prometheus and file surfacers are enabled automatically.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>